# SENOU LYNN

550 South Willard Street, Burlington, VT 05401 | senou.lynn@gmail.com | 802.829.0160 | linkedin.com/in/senou-lynn-44857a11a/

## FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

I was born in Africa and have lived in 6 countries prior to settling down in the northeast U.S. The common threads of my interests revolve around pushing boundaries and expanding comfort zones through high risk, creative, mental and physical activities while striving towards excellence and proficiency. The combination of my experiences travelling internationally, fearlessly pursuing new interests, and my solid work history has culminated in a well-rounded skillset that includes organization, perseverance, loyalty, tenacity, multi-cultural sensitivity, and creative problem solving.

Languages
Frameworks
Databases.
Source Control
Graphic Design/Content Creation
Audio Production/Editing

JavaScript | CSS | HTML
React | Node.js | Express| Sass
MongoDB | Firebase
Git | GitHub
Figma | GIMP | Photoshop | Canva
Engineering (live and studio) | Pro Tools | Ableton | Logic X

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OUT Maine Rockland, ME Mar 2021 – Apr 2021

Focused on supporting, educating, and empowering LGBTQ+ youth through building welcoming communities in Maine.

### Developer - Capstone Project, Burlington Code Academy

Member of a 4-person team tasked with significant revamping of the online resource library, adding dynamic search capabilities, and creating an efficient resource management portal. Incorporated agile methodology, collaborative pair programming, and regular and frequent client check-ins.

- · Interpreted client styling while introducing mobile responsiveness and accessibility
- Implemented Algolia framework to create faceted and open-text search capabilities rendering real-time, user-friendly results
- Created admin portal optimized with full CRUD functionality for straightforward resource management
- · Participated in teamwide research to determine the optimal set of frameworks based on project objectives
- Organized daily stand-up meetings to manage versions and feature additions and maintain cohesive creative vision
- Technology used included a FERN Stack (Firebase, Express, React, Node.js), Algolia, CSS3, and GitHub

<u>Vermont Restaurants</u> Richmond and Burlington, VT Sep 2016 – Current

Stone Corral Brewery, Richmond, VT E.B. Strong's Prime Steakhouse, Burlington, VT Tap Room Staff Server / Bartender Jun 2020 – Current Sep 2016 – Current

At <u>Stone Corral</u>, provide exceptional service at a fast-paced brewpub with rotating selection of craft beer and food made with local, fresh ingredients. Role requires a high level of knowledge regarding varieties of beers and brew processes. At <u>E.B. Strong's</u>, provide meticulous fine dining experience, communicating current wine, food, and special information to customers. Bartend and serve political, corporate, and festive events with focus on classic cocktails, local beer, spirits, and wine.

Coconut Tree Divers Roatan, Honduras Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

**Divemaster** – Led customer dives, navigated local dive sites, identified marine flora/fauna, and assessed and managed risk while upholding safety standards. Also taught diving classes to 1-12 divers of various skill levels.

- Certified up through Divermaster; assisted instructor certifications from Discover Scuba Diver to Rescue Diver
- Nitrox certified with specialties including Night, Deep Dive (up to 130ft), Peak Buoyancy, Underwater Search and Nav.

The Lip Burlington, VT Jun 2018 – Jun 2020

**Co-founder** – Coordinated local, national, and international artist bookings. Managed a small team, oversaw social media, graphic design, organization finances/artist payout. Provided live sound tech, security, venue upkeep, and maintenance.

**Surveyor/Data Analyst** – Worked with St. Lucian Ministry of Commerce to develop and implement a survey instrument assessing the effect of recent Value Added Tax implementation.

- · Surveyed several hundred consumers; compiled and analyzed data into excel and SPSS workbooks
- Presented findings to the CAD during nationally televised event along with a submitted written report

New York. NY

#### INTERNSHIPS

MacroPolicy Perspectives

Jun 2017 - Aug 2018

**Econometrics Intern** – Collected historic data on 12 state-level macroeconomic indicators including annual tax revenue, population and migration trends, and spending patterns. Organized and manipulated data in Microsoft Excel workbooks and created visual representations to convey information to employer.

Heady Vermont Burlington, VT Sep 2016 – Sep 2017

**Social Media and Event Management Intern** – Developed brand image and social media marketing strategy and worked events.

• Helped co-owners organize, market, and run first Hemp Fest

# **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate (480+ hours)

Burlington Code Academy

Apr 2021

BS, Community Development and Applied Economics University of Vermont Dec 2018

Special interest in macro-economics and international development; field and real-world experiential learning

Focus on studio production and music technology

BS, Biology-Track Coursework Concordia University Sep 2012 – May 2014
Inbound Certification HubSpot May 2021

#### COMMUNITY

UVM Outing Club	Leader	Aug 2015 – May 2018
Headcount	Voting Registration Volunteer	Jun 2016 – Jun 2017
UVM	Alternative Spring Break Leader	Sep 2016 – Mar 2017
Big Brothers Big Sisters	Big Brother	Jan 2012 – May 2012
Brattleboro Hockey Association	Youth Referee / Time-Box Volunteer	Sep 2010 – May 2012

# **O**THER INTERESTS

Scuba Diving

Back-country Skiing

Multi-pitch Rock Climbing

Long-Distance Hiking

Marine / Coral Conservation

• International Travel / Adventure

· Guitar and Drums / Sound Design

Photography

Cooking / Cocktail Science